

CONTACTS

Bari - Italy

+39 333 62 56 401

giuseppe.toto@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/giuseppe-toto

My Work Portfolio

CORE SKILLS

- GAMING
 - o Unity, Unity Editor
 - o Asynchronous programming
 - o C#, Rider
- WEB:
 - o Laravel, Php
 - o API Rest
 - o Javascript, React
- DATABASE
 - o MySQL
 - o PostgreSQL
- **DEPLOYMENT**
 - o Docker
 - o Fastlane
- Git
- Test Driven Development
- Design Patterns

SOFT SKILLS

- Mentoring
- Proactivity
- Rapid Prototyping
- Rapidity of learning new technologies
- Ownership
- Excellent communication with stakeholders involved in the project (dev and not-dev)
- Development of market changedriven software solutions

Giuseppe Toto

Unity Developer | Full Stack Developer

ABOUT ME

I have 15 years of experience in software development and in coordinating web, mobile and gaming applications, working with companies and startups that are strongly focused on innovation.

In recent years, my focus has been in Unity and C# working for companies focused on serious games.

I am versatile since during this years I used several technologies and learned new skills when needed, thanks to my full stack mindset. I have worked in the web development field since the start of my career (Laravel/PHP, React/ Javascript, HTML/CSS, API REST, Python, etc.)

I love developing quality code, attending developer meetups, participating in hackathons, talk about agile, design patterns and testing.

I enjoy working in an environment where proactivity and motivation are rewarded.

I am on the board of the "Club degli sviluppatori - Puglia" the largest community of developers in Apulia - Italy, where we organise meetings to talk about the most common technologies and problems in our industry.

RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Unity Developer - Marshmallow Games SRL June 2021 - Present

Smart Tales is an educational mobile application for children with a monthly traffic of thousands of user sessions, that has been awarded several times by Apple Italy. It offers a library of stories and interactive games to teach children as young as 3 years of age about STEM subjects.

My roles:

- software architecture definition, rapid prototyping, C#, UI implementation, Firebase, dynamic asset management, IAP, refactoring, design pattern, API REST, localization, automatic release with Fastlane.
- Lead Unity Developer Swipe Story SRL

Ott. 2015 - June 2022

Swipe Story is a platform for creating interactive stories to valorise the culture of local areas.

My roles:

- Design and development of a tool in Unity in no-code mode for creating interactive stories with gamification dynamics.
- Team leader, C# development, Unit Test, UI implementation, API REST and database development, localization, dynamic asset management, automated release with Fastlane.
- Fullstack Mobile and Web Developer Stentle SRL 2014 - 2018

Stentle SRL is a B2B company for innovative e-commerce development. My roles:

 Frontend/backend development with Laravel/React, HTML/CSS skinning, API REST integration, Docker deployment, etc.

EDUCATION

- MIP Politecnico di Milano Graduate School of Business Summer startup program in 2012
- BSc in "Computer Science" with First Class Honours at University of Bari - Italy in 2011
- Diploma in Abacus Computer Science at I.T.S.I. Marconi Bari Italy